# **Atul Jayant Jairam**

Montreal, QC (514) 814-0465

atuljayant465@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/AtulJairam465/

English Hindi

# **Front End Developer**

#### **Profile**

Enthusiastic IT professional with 4 years of experience in the Health Care IT Industry. Skilled in Databases and various Web Technology Domains like Angular JS, React, and NodeJS. I have completed my intensive studies in Programming and Web Technologies from Institut superieur d'informatique to enhance my skills in this field. I am organized, hardworking and versatile with excellent problem-solving skills. I am a philomath and adaptive to any recent technology that would challenge and help me explore my limits.

### **Skills**

Operating systems	Microsoft Windows (8/10/11),
	Linux: CentOS
Programming Languages	C++, JavaScript, Golang, PhP, Java, Android.
Technologies	AngularJS, ReactJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Flutter, NodeJS, MySQL, MSSQL, GitHub, AZURE, Docker.
Tools	PhpStorm, IntelliJ Community edition, Visual Studio Code, VS Enterprise, Android Studio, Docker Compose, JIRA.

## **Professional Experiences**

## **Software Specialist**

eClinicalWorks. India

Aug 2017 - Feb 2021

- Worked on Health Care Medical Record application which was used by providers based in the US. Worked on tickets that had issues with the description production application.
- Analyzed the application to seek out any issues and performed regression tests.
- Investigated and troubleshot the issues with the tickets.
- Performed maintenance on Apache servers.
- Performed manual testing on the application.
- Worked on web developer tools to find bugs within the application.
- Worked on technologies: MSSQL, MySQL, Java, Azure.
- Worked on JIRA, AzuzeDevOps, and Github for version control.

### **Software Developer Intern**

July 2021 - Sept 2021

Shuja Bits, India

- Developed web application on C# and Angular.
- Coordinated with the client to understand the requirements and changes in the project.
- Used AzureDevOps for code versioning of the project. Followed Agile Scrum Methodology for the management of the Projects. Worked on Visual Studio Enterprise for code integration
- Worked on Azure services for hosting the development database. Also worked on Technologies: C#, Angular, NodeJS, MSSQL, Azure.
- Created the database schemas for the table and the data. Performed and created manual test cases.

## **Projects**

## The Weather App

This application was developed to show the weather of all the cities in the world. It can take any language and show the output for that city. The application was created using Restful/REST API, NodeJS, and ReactJs.

https://github.com/WhiteFang465/w13\_node\_react/tree/main/final\_practical\_exam

#### **AnimeWorld**

An application that gives access to information for all the Animes. You can save and get information about your favorite animes. the technology for this project is Android, Room Database, and was developed using Android Studio.

#### **FotoRama**

This project is an image uploading application that uploads high-resolution images of a 16:9 aspect ratio. This was a group project and I worked as a Scrum Master wherein I was responsible to manage and create tickets for the project and developing the backend API for the project. The technologies used are NodeJS, Flutter, and MySQL and the tools used for development were IntelliJ Idea and Docker Compose.

#### Education

# **Programming and Web Technologies,** Attestation of College Studies Institut superieur d'informatique – Montreal, Quebec

2021 - ...

Information Technology, Bachelor's Degree

Bharati Vidyapeeth College of Engineering - Navi Mumbai, India

2013-2017

## **Other Experience**

## **Reception Worker (Condensing Team)**

Oct 2021 - present

Lufa Farms, Montreal

- Receiving and putting products away.
- Checking the inventory for issues.
- Condensing the inventory.
- Ensure the freezers are always clean.